<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About Me on Ethan Holleman</title>
    <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About Me on Ethan Holleman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ethanholleman.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Casual virtual Poker with Zoom and PlayingCards.io</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/zoom_poker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/zoom_poker/</guid>
      <description>Recently a few of my friends and I wanted to do virtual Poker night. We where not interested in playing for cash and so I started looking around for an online platform to make it happen.
Pretty much everything that comes up with a cursory google search did not satify my basic requirements but eventually I came across PlayingCards.io which provided what I think is the best solution for free, causal quaruntine poker nights.
Step 1 is to set up your &amp;ldquo;table&amp;rdquo; with PlayingCards. Use this link to start building a table. Later once you finish setting everything up you can share the link to the table and others will be able to join, see and manipulate the objects on the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data and the Vietnam War</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/vietnam_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/vietnam_data/</guid>
      <description>Turing the jungle into punchcards During the early optimistic days of the summer 2020 quarantine I watched Ken Burn&amp;rsquo;s fantastic 10 part 18-hour series on the Vietnam war. It is by far the most accessible and compressive body of work on the subject. Burn&amp;rsquo;s starts you off pre-WWI so you really get a comprehensive picture of things.
One of the aspects of the war that fascinated me the most was the push by the the then Secretary of Defense, Robert McNamara, to quantify as much of the war as was computationally possible. One of the most storage intensive of McNamara&amp;rsquo;s efforts was the Hamlet Evaluation System, which attempted to quantify the degree to which ~12,000 small, rural Vietnamese villages had been pacified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fishing at Putah Creek</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/putah_fishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/putah_fishing/</guid>
      <description>Day trip out to Putah Creek in Winters CA.
A few turkeys we saw before leaving Davis.
The spot in the creek we picked out.
Erica practicing casting.
Testing out the waders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polo</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/projects/polo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 13:49:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/projects/polo/</guid>
      <description>This was a project I worked on as part of the BioXFEL summer internship program. I worked with Dr. Sarah Bowman and other members of Hauptman-Woodward Medical Research Institute (HWI).
If you are short on time and don&amp;rsquo;t want to read these entire post here are the important links.
 Polo website Polo poster Video Presentation  So what is &amp;ldquo;high-throughput crystallography&amp;rdquo;? Lets say you are a researcher, trying to develop a treatment for a novel virus that is quickly spreading across the globe. You know that the binding between the viruses outer spike protein and a receptor on the cells of lung tissue is critical to the pathogens virulence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redtail Catfish</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/wiki_blog/redtail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 13:49:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/wiki_blog/redtail/</guid>
      <description>The redtail catfish Link to article
Recently my late night TV show of choice as been River Monsters with Jeremy Wade which surprisingly strikes the perfect balance of cheesy reality TV and wildly educational programming and so I have been googling the various types of freshwater fish that Jeremy encounters.
I am particularly fond of Phractocephalus hemioliopterus; the red tailed catfish.
  Image of a red tailed catfish. By Serstef - Own work, CC BY-SA 4.0, https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=54607456   It is currently the only extant species of the Phractocephalus genus and is noted for its potential to grow to massive sizes (hence its River Monster&amp;rsquo;s cameo) reaching up to 6 feet long and 180 pounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using local R packages on UC Davis Genome Center cluster</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/genome_cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/genome_cluster/</guid>
      <description>I ran into a few issues trying to figure out how to run batch scripts on the Genome Center cluster. One of the least documented and hardest to figure out was how to successfully load R packages I had installed to my user directory.
For example I would start R and install a package I needed and load the library with no problem.
The code below would run without a problem.
install.packages(&amp;quot;glmnet&amp;quot;) library(glmnet)  But then calling the running the same script from a batch file fails to import the library.
I tried multiple possible fixes with no success until I was tipped of by a current lab member about the magic word.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
