<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blogs on Ethan Holleman</title>
    <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/tags/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blogs on Ethan Holleman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ethanholleman.github.io/tags/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Make custom Skribbl.io word banks using Reddit and Praw</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/skribbl.io_words/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/skribbl.io_words/</guid>
      <description>Skribbl.io is a great free quarantine / social distanced game where one person attempts to draw a word while everyone else guesses what they are drawing. When setting up the game you can supply your own list of comma separated words doing the game.
The problem with doing this manually is that one person playing will know all the words.
For an upcoming Zoom party I created a python command line application that takes in subreddit names and a few other parameters and using the Praw library retrieves the most commonly used words from the top comments of posts to a subreddit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting COVID-19 Hospitalization Geo-Spacial Data</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/covid_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/covid_data/</guid>
      <description>After finding the COG-UK data I was looking around for other interesting COVID-19 datasets to play around with and build my R plotting skills with.
User moritz.kraemer posted this article on early case descriptions which included a lot of geo-spacial data that I was interested in takeing a look at.
There was a significant number of fields devoted to hospitalization related measurements and so I focused on that subject for the plot below.
The dataset includes patients with and without hospitalization records and so first I filtered down to just those with records and those who also had location data. This subset of patients formed subplot A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting COG-UK Data</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/cog_sars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/cog_sars/</guid>
      <description>The Covid-19 Genomics UK Consortium has been collecting and sequencing thousands of COVID-19 genomes from patients in the UK and around the world.
All of their data is publicly available. Here I played around with the phylogenetic tree they have created from global alignments of all the genomes they have sequenced.
You can download the tree in Newick format from their data page which also hosts sequences and the alignment files.
Visualizing the COVID-19 phylogenetic tree by country of origin Genome count by country Note this plot is log scale in the y-axis.
16 most prevalent UK COVID-19 lineages Density plots showing the number of genomes of the 16 most prevalent lineages detected by COG-UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Christmas Card Bonus Pictures</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/christmas_card/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/christmas_card/</guid>
      <description>Apartment Tour Taken right after move in.
Skys during the wildfires Those are not clouds.
Davis campus cows Around Davis Hiking in Winters, CA
Fishing at Putah Creek
Thanksgiving Bubbles Lots cat pictures have been taken
California changes a man </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poker Nights Running Results</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/running_winnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/running_winnings/</guid>
      <description>Running stack sizes Shows each players cumulative stack over all nights played.
 Winnings by date Plot of each players winnings (stack at the end of the night - buy in) over time.
 All games have been played virtually, for info on how we host these see this post</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Casual virtual Poker with Zoom and PlayingCards.io</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/zoom_poker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/zoom_poker/</guid>
      <description>Recently a few of my friends and I wanted to do virtual Poker night. We where not interested in playing for cash and so I started looking around for an online platform to make it happen.
Pretty much everything that comes up with a cursory google search did not satisfy my basic requirements but eventually I came across PlayingCards.io which provided what I think is the best solution for free, causal quarantine poker nights.
Step 1 is to set up your &amp;ldquo;table&amp;rdquo; with PlayingCards. Use this link to start building a table. Later once you finish setting everything up you can share the link to the table and others will be able to join, see and manipulate the objects on the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data and the Vietnam War</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/vietnam_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/vietnam_data/</guid>
      <description>Turning the jungle into punch cards During the early optimistic days of the summer 2020 quarantine I watched Ken Burn&amp;rsquo;s fantastic 10 part 18-hour series on the Vietnam war. It is by far the most accessible and compressive body of work on the subject. Burn&amp;rsquo;s starts you off pre-WWI so you really get a comprehensive picture of things.
One of the aspects of the war that fascinated me the most was the push by the the then Secretary of Defense, Robert McNamara, to quantify as much of the war as was computationally possible. One of the most storage intensive of McNamara&amp;rsquo;s efforts was the Hamlet Evaluation System, which attempted to quantify the degree to which ~12,000 small, rural Vietnamese villages had been pacified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fishing at Putah Creek</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/putah_fishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/putah_fishing/</guid>
      <description>Day trip out to Putah Creek in Winters CA.
A few turkeys we saw before leaving Davis.
The spot in the creek we picked out.
Erica practicing casting.
Testing out the waders.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
