<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3D Printing on Ethan Holleman</title>
    <link>https://ethanholleman.com/tags/3d-printing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3D Printing on Ethan Holleman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ethanholleman.com/tags/3d-printing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why are (some) maker spaces so empty?</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.com/posts/why-are-maker-spaces-empty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.com/posts/why-are-maker-spaces-empty/</guid>
      <description>Where is everyone? I am lucky to live within biking distance of the Davis Craft Center, an excellent facility that provides screen printing, woodworking, welding, and &amp;ldquo;maker&amp;rdquo; resources (3D printer, laser cutter, soldering kit, etc.) to UC Davis students and community members at very reasonable prices.
I only learned about the maker space at the Craft center within the last three months; since then have been visiting semi-regularly to work on my projects. The main benefit of working there for me is that there is significantly more space compared to my one bedroom apartment and it is cat free. This is especially helpful when working with anything remotely string shaped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Pico W LED 3D print status monitor</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.com/posts/pico-print-status-indicator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.com/posts/pico-print-status-indicator/</guid>
      <description>I am almost constantly running my 3D printer. Usually the only time it is not pumping plastic is when the laundry machine is running. Both the printer and laundry machine are plugged into the same outlet and for some reason having them both running at the same time can occasionally cause the printer to freeze and stop.
If the girlfriend wants to start a load of laundry a common question she has for me is &amp;ldquo;How long is left on this print?&amp;rdquo; since she is nice enough to not want to risk my print failing.
So I wanted to create a quick and easy to read indicator for how far along my printer is through a print and came up with the solution described below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rejoice, the golden age of Nerf is upon us! A general overview of the state of hobby grade and competitive foam dart tag</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.com/posts/hobby-grade-nerf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.com/posts/hobby-grade-nerf/</guid>
      <description>It is likely you have come into contact with the Nerf brand at some point in your life. Hasbro&amp;rsquo;s iconic line of foam flinging mechanisms, until recently, held a near complete monopoly on the hobby. While Nerf blasters remain fun for casual around-the-house or workplace battles, for many, they simply do not pack enough of a punch. There has always been a small continent of nerds who longed to maintain the goofy persona that Nerf affords with its bright colors, oversized projectiles, and exaggerated designs but push the limits of their blasters. These early &amp;ldquo;hobby grade&amp;rdquo; Nerfers modified existing blasters and even constructed completely original designs using parts you could buy from a hardware store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Print TPU without a direct drive extruder</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.com/posts/print_tpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.com/posts/print_tpu/</guid>
      <description>These recommendations are in addition to general 3D printing best practices, namely proper bed leveling and cleaning. Without a clean and level bed, none of this advice will do you any good.
1. Print a filament guide; preferably one that uses a bearing for your printer I print on an Ender3 and use this guide by Mark Villela. A filament guide is an abosulte requirement to reduce the angle the filament must enter the extruder gear at. Without one, the tension on the filament at the extruder will be to great for it to push filament into the hot end.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
