<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Ethan Holleman</title>
    <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Ethan Holleman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ethanholleman.github.io/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Plotting COVID-19 Hospitalization Geo-Spacial Data</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/covid_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/covid_data/</guid>
      <description>After finding the COG-UK data I was looking around for other interesting COVID-19 datasets to play around with and build my R plotting skills with.
User moritz.kraemer posted this article on early case descriptions which included a lot of geo-spacial data that I was interested in takeing a look at.
There was a significant number of fields devoted to hospitalization related measurements and so I focused on that subject for the plot below.
The dataset includes patients with and without hospitalization records and so first I filtered down to just those with records and those who also had location data. This subset of patients formed subplot A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting COG-UK Data</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/cog_sars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/cog_sars/</guid>
      <description>The Covid-19 Genomics UK Consortium has been collecting and sequencing thousands of COVID-19 genomes from patients in the UK and around the world.
All of their data is publicly available. Here I played around with the phylogenetic tree they have created from global alignments of all the genomes they have sequenced.
You can download the tree in Newick format from their data page which also hosts sequences and the alignment files.
Visualizing the COVID-19 phylogenetic tree by country of origin Genome count by country Note this plot is log scale in the y-axis.
16 most prevalent UK COVID-19 lineages Density plots showing the number of genomes of the 16 most prevalent lineages detected by COG-UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polo</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/projects/polo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 13:49:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/projects/polo/</guid>
      <description>This was a project I worked on as part of the BioXFEL summer internship program. I worked with Dr. Sarah Bowman and other members of Hauptman-Woodward Medical Research Institute (HWI).
If you are short on time and don&amp;rsquo;t want to read these entire post here are the important links.
 Polo website Polo poster Video Presentation  So what is &amp;ldquo;high-throughput crystallography&amp;rdquo;? Lets say you are a researcher, trying to develop a treatment for a novel virus that is quickly spreading across the globe. You know that the binding between the viruses outer spike protein and a receptor on the cells of lung tissue is critical to the pathogens virulence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using local R packages on UC Davis Genome Center cluster</title>
      <link>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/genome_cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanholleman.github.io/posts/genome_cluster/</guid>
      <description>I ran into a few issues trying to figure out how to run batch scripts on the Genome Center cluster. One of the least documented and hardest to figure out was how to successfully load R packages I had installed to my user directory.
For example I would start R and install a package I needed and load the library with no problem.
The code below would run without a problem.
install.packages(&amp;quot;glmnet&amp;quot;) library(glmnet)  But then calling the running the same script from a batch file fails to import the library.
I tried multiple possible fixes with no success until I was tipped of by a current lab member about the magic word.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
